Mobile Suit
Rage on! Rage on! Rage on! Gundam!
Moeagare! Moeagare! Moeagare GANDAMU!
You must run forth!
Kimi yo hashire
If you are still burning with furious rage...
Mada ikari ni moeru toshi ga aru nara...
You must fight the towering foe!
Kyodai na teki o
Fight! Fight! Fight!
Uteyo! Uteyo! Uteyo!
Bring to bear the rage of justice, Gundam
Seigi no ikari o butsukero GANDAMU
Mobile Suit Gundam! Gundam!
Kidou senshi GANDAMU! GANDAMU!
Rise once more! Rise once more!
Yomigaeru! Yomigaeru!
Rise once more! Gundam!
Yomigaeru GANDAMU!
You must seize the power!
Kimi yo tsukame
Fly toward the galaxy, Gundam!
Ginga e mukatte tobeyo GANDAMU
Mobile Suit Gundam! Gundam!
Kidou senshi GANDAMU! GANDAMU!
The Zabi family seeks to impose dictatorship
over all of humanity...
...ruling from the Principality of Zeon...
...a gigantic space city-state
floating beyond the moon.
In order to defeat this dictatorship...
...the Earth Federation continues
its stubborn resistance...
...on Earth and in space.
Meanwhile...
...the White Base evaded an attack
from a Zeon space cruiser...
...and escaped from the space city Side 7,
eventually landing on Earth.
However, without a chance to contact
the Federation Forces...
...the young crew was forced
to continue fighting.
It was an endless series
of terrifying encounters.
Coming Home
Here we go...!
What's this? What's this? Whoa...!
Hee! Cut that out!
Having the sunlight shine from one place...
It all seems so artificial.
But you know...
this is what they call nature.
That's true. When they talk of
the infinite expanse of space...
...I guess this is what they mean.
Where's Amuro?
He went to see his mother.
Oh, was that his Core Fighter just now?
He said his hometown was
about 30 km east of here.
Heh! I feel like I've been betrayed.
So he's one of the elite, eh?
Not everyone living on Earth
is part of the elite.
In fact, Amuro's father lived in space...
...and Amuro has never really lived
with his mother.
Just having a home on Earth
makes him elite.
Seems like there were
a lot of air strikes around here.
I hope it's safe.
I wonder.
I hear there's guerrilla fighting here, too.
I'm sure Mother's not injured, but...
Bring us some booze!
Oopsy-daisy...
Who are you?!
This is my house.
What?!
Stop it!
But this punk...
Damn, it's empty.
Sorry we entered your house
without permission.
But there was no one here.
No one here?!
It's an abandoned house.
An abandoned house?!
Mother!
Mother...? Mother, huh?
He doesn't believe me!
Maybe she died running away.
If you don't want to be apart from Amuro,
you should come with us.
But going to space is...
You should see the construction
of the Side. It's magnificent.
I want Amuro to see it.
I understand that.
But I don't think I can...
Forgive me, Amuro.
I just can't get used to living In space.
What's wrong, little boy?
Playing house?
Or do you miss your mommy?
Please...
Please pay for that.
This is all we have to live on.
Please pay me for that.
Oh, fine.
Here.
Stop, ma'am!
Don't pick it up!
Have the soldier pick it up for you!
Who the hell is that?!
That boy...
- Why don't you say that again, kid?!
- Insolent brat!
I-I said pick it up.
What did you say, you little...!
Pick it up!
Pick it up! Pick it up!
Why you...!
You...
Bastard!
What the hell
would a kid like you know?!
If we weren't here, this town would've
belonged to Zeon long ago.
Self-important brat!
I remember...!
That boy's Amuro!
He was a friend of my daughter's!
Please stop! He's just a child!
- What?! How dare you...!
I'll give you back your money...
...so, please go.
The soldiers who survived
were abandoned by headquarters.
No allies came to help them,
so that's how they ended up.
War is really terrible.
I see... So Comilly is dead.
It's not just my daughter. My husband, too.
Being left alive and alone is a cruel fate.
You've seen your mother, right?
No.
Oh? Didn't you get her letter?
Your mother's a volunteer
at the refugee camp.
S-She's alive?!
Do you remember the church over there?
The hill back there,
where you used to play with Comilly.
Thank you, ma'am!
Be careful out there!
The enemy's completely retreated.
With not one fighter to greet us...
...these guns will start to rust.
This is part of our job, too.
This is Luggun 3.
All is normal in Area 304.
Roger.
All hands, return to ship! Return to ship!
Enemy aircraft sighted!
Prepare for anti-air combat!
Enemies?!
Yes. There's no friendly IFF signal!
10 km out at sea, and approaching.
Shall we mobilize the White Base?
No. They'll spot us more easily.
You're right.
We'll be in trouble if they
contact their main force.
Let's take the initiative
and shoot them down.
Yes.
Core Fighter,
launch preparations complete!
Okay, your launch path is clear.
Core Fighter, you may launch when ready.
Roger! I'm off!
Something's coming!
The enemy?!
Looks like a fighter. Damn! He's behind us!
What?!
You're too late!
Descend!
I won't let you get away!
Fire! Fire!
Damn! And they're only a patrol craft!
This is it. This is where Mother is.
Hey! Something's coming!
An airplane!
Let's check it out!
Yeah!
Hey, isn't that a Federation fighter?
It sure is.
This isn't good.
Wow! Cool!
It's a real fighter!
It's so cool!
Wait just a minute.
Huh?
You're a soldier, aren't you?
I don't know what you're here for...
...but could you hide that fighter right away?
Why is that? I'm just...
Well, your enemy has a forward base
just beyond those mountains.
And they come around on patrol
once a day.
The enemy may have
already detected you.
You can attend to your business afterwards.
I... understand.
Amuro... Is it really you, Amuro...?
Amuro!
M-Mother!
Mother!
Lucky him...
Sorry, but can you deal with the fighter?
Oh, that's right.
Amuro, go hide it quickly.
We'll talk after that.
Okay.
- Is that your son?
- Yes.
So, the Zeons even attacked
that backwater of a Side...
Then I guess we don't know if your father...
More soldiers showed up!
Don't move, understand?
Mobile Suit
Gundam
Oh yeah? Watch this!
What kind of fighter is that?
I don't know...!
This is Hot Dog patrol!
Enemy fighter sighted!
Current position, Y-207!
Oh no! Look over there!
What?!
Gotcha!
You're finished!
I must be leaking fuel!
Bright! Looks like they got my fuel tank!
The enemy craft is damaged,
but it got away.
What?! Can't you confirm?
I can't stick around any longer!
Operators, can you calculate
the enemy's escape route?
All I can tell is that it's southwest.
Toward Amuro's hometown.
I'll contact him.
Ryu, can you get back to ship?
That's no problem, but...
I'll have Amuro do the rest.
Sorry!
Sayla! Send Amuro an emergency sign!
Hurry!
Yes, sir!
Right. Everyone stay still.
Nobody move.
We have a report that an enemy fighter
landed near here.
Anyone know about it?
Hey, kid. You know anything about a plane?
You can tell me about it,
just between you and me. Okay?
How would I know!
Looks like we're not popular here.
Here, have some chocolate.
I don't want it!
Give me back my mom and dad!
Stop that.
How frightening!
You lost your chance to have chocolate, kid.
What's that sound!
How could they signal me
at a time like this?
I said, what was that?!
Speak!
I'm turning 89 years old.
Hey, lady!
Who's sleeping in the bed there?
Just one of the injured. Nobody special...
Show me!
He's my son! He's injured!
If you've got nothing to hide, then show us!
Amuro! Wait!
A-Amuro! Amuro!
Amuro!
He's going to live. Call a doctor!
Even they might have children, you know.
How can you aim a gun
at someone like that, and fire?
You've grown so cruel.
Then... Mother, are you saying
that you don't care if I get killed?!
Th-This is war!
That's true, but...!
That's true, but it's not right
to point guns at people!
Mother... Mother don't you...
I...
Don't you love me...?
How can you...!
How could a mother not love her child?
Liar!
Amuro!
Amuro, is something wrong?
No.
I see.
We have an emergency.
A Zeon patrol plane is headed that way.
Be careful.
The White Base will launch
and rendezvous with you.
Roger!
Amuro, I don't remember
bringing you up to be like this.
Please go back to the way you were!
Right now... we're at war!
What a disgraceful child!
Is that it?
I'll get them!
Where are they heading?
Is there a base?
I don't care if there's a base or not!
Damn! They didn't make it back!
Hurry with anti-aircraft fire!
Launch Dopps!
Missed!
I won't let you...!
Gunperry?!
I get it! They brought the Gundam!
All right, then!
Hey, Amuro!
Wanna try a mid-air transfer?
A mid-air transfer?!
Yeah, let's try testing it in combat!
We can't, Mr. Kai.
We haven't tested the docking parts
Ms. Matilda brought us.
Amuro says he wants to try it, so why not?
It's not my call.
Maybe it's because he was raised by a man.
He wasn't like that as a boy.
He was a boy who couldn't even kill a fly.
Vertical distance, 50 meters!
Activate docking searcher!
Laser searcher synchronized!
5... 4... 3...
2... 1...
Gundam B Parts released!
Core Change! Docking, go!
All right, good job!
Gundam A Parts released!
That damn Kai!
It's not synchronized!
That Amuro! What is he doing?!
He's going after the enemy base, right?
What's the point in hitting a forward base
in such a backwater region?
And that Kai. Docking the Gundam
in battle without testing it.
They're just wasting ammunition!
In our situation,
it's like cutting our own throats!
Mr. Bright...!
Am I wrong?
No.
You don't want to stay?
It's not about what I want.
That's where my comrades are.
You must be his mother.
Thank you for taking care of Amuro.
Not at all. Amuro has saved us
on many occasions.
That can't be...
It's the truth.
His work today was truly impressive.
Oh, is that so...
Amuro, what will you do?
We will be leaving shortly, but...
Ah, yes.
Take care of yourself...
...Mother.
Excuse us.
We will watch over your son.
Amuro...
White Base isn't the only unit
short on weapons and ammunition.
Chief Cuaran's cunning attack
on the Gundam...
...is enough to bring terror
to Amuro and crew...
...as they bravely fight the Gundam.
Will Amuro be able to survive the assault?
Mobile Suit Gundam. Next episode...
Time, Be Still.
Next Time
Time, Be Still
Will you be able to survive?
Amuro, do not look back
The star shining far off in space...
Amuro, it's your homeland where you were born
Do you remember the days of your childhood?
The morning when you woke up in warmth?
Amuro, do not look back, Amuro...
A man must hide his tears, hide his tears
Only look to tomorrow, to tomorrow forever...